In the 17th century, a woman named Giulia Tofana
في القرن 17 كان يوجد أمرأة اسمها جوليانا توفانا
had a very successful perfume business.
تمتلك تجارة مزدهره جداً لبيع العطور .
For over 50 years she ran it.
و بقيت تديرها على مدى 50 عاماً
It sort of ended abruptly when she was executed — (Laughter) —
إنتهى الأمر نوعاً ما بطريقةٍ فجائية حين تم اعدامها (ضحك)
for murdering 600 men. You see, it wasn't a very good perfume.
لأنها قتلت 600 رجل. في الواقع، لم تكون العطور جيدةً جداً
In fact, it was completely odorless and tasteless and colorless,
في الحقيقة, كانت معدومة الرائحة و الطعم و اللون
but as a poison, it was the best money could buy,
لكن كونه سماً ، فقد كان أفضل ما يمكن للمال أن يشتريه
so women flocked to her in order to murder their husbands.
لذا هرعت النساء إليها من أجل قتل أزواجهن
It turns out that poisoners were a valued and feared group,
وإتضح أن المسممين كانوا مجموعة قيمة و مهابة
because poisoning a human being is a quite difficult thing.
فتسميم انسان هو أمر في غاية الصعوبة
The reason is, we have sort of a built-in poison detector.
السبب هو ان لدينا كاشف سموم مدمج فينا.
You can see this as early as even in newborn infants.
يمكن أن ترى ذلك في فترةٍ مبكرة حتى عند الرضع
If you are willing to do this, you can take a couple of drops
إذا كنت مستعداً للقيام بهذا، خذ قطرتين
of a bitter substance or a sour substance,
من محلول حامض أو مرٍ
and you'll see that face, the tongue stick out, the wrinkled nose,
و سترى ذلك الوجه : اللسان يمتد و الأنف يتجعد
as if they're trying to get rid of what's in their mouth.
وكأنهما يريدان التخلص مما يوجد في الفم
This reaction expands into adulthood and becomes
و يتواصل رد الفعل هذا إلى سن الرشد ليصبح
sort of a full-blown disgust response, no longer just
نوعاً من ردود الفعل الناضجة للتعبير عن القرف و ليس فقط
about whether or not we're about to be poisoned,
إذا ما وقع تسميمنا أم لا
but whenever there's a threat of physical contamination
بل كذلك في حال حدوث تلوث جسدي
from some source. But the face remains strikingly similar.
من مصدر معين و لكن يبقى الوجه مشابهاً بصفةٍ ملحوظة
It has expanded more, though, than just keeping us away
مع ذلك فقد تطورت أكثر من مجرد ابقائنا بعيدين
from physical contaminants, and there's a growing
عن التلوث الجسدي وهنالك
body of evidence to suggest that, in fact, this emotion
براهين متزايدة تشير في الواقع أن هذا التعبير
of disgust now influences our moral beliefs
عن القرف أصبح يؤثر على معتقداتنا الأخلاقية
and even our deeply held political intuitions.
و حتى خيراتنا السياسية الراسخة
Why this might be the case?
لما ذلك؟؟
We can understand this process by understanding
يمكننا أن نفهم هذه الطريقة من خلال فهم
a little bit about emotions in general. So the basic human emotions,
القليل فيما يتعلق بالعواطف عموماً. إن العواطف البشرية عامةً
those kinds of emotions that we share with all other human beings,
و التي نشترك فيها مع جميع البشر الأخرين
exist because they motivate us to do good things
تخرج لأنها تدفعنا للقيام بأشياء جيدة
and they keep us away from doing bad things.
وهي تمنعنا من القيام بأشياء سيئة
So by and large, they are good for our survival.
لذا فهي بشكلٍ عام جيدة من أجل بقائنا .
Take the emotion of fear, for instance. It keeps us away
فالإحساس بالخوف مثلا يمنعنا
from doing things that are really, really risky.
من القيام بالأشياء التي هي خطيرةٌ جداً
This photo taken just before his death — (Laughter) —
أخذت هذه الصورة قبل وفاته تماماً- (ضحك)-
is actually a — No, one reason this photo is interesting
.هي في الواقع - لا هذه الصورة مثيرةٌ للإنتباه
is because most people would not do this, and if they did,
لأن معظم الأشخاص لن يفعل ذلك و في حال ما فعلوا
they would not live to tell it, because fear would have
فإنهم لن يعيشوا ليرووا التجربة لأن الخوف
kicked in a long time ago to a natural predator.
سيبدأ في العمل منذ وقتٍ طويل لإبعادنا عن المفترس الطبيعي
Just like fear offers us protective benefits, disgust seems
مثلما يمنحنا الخوف فوائد حمائية ، يبدو أن الشعور بالقرف
to do the same thing, except for what disgust does is
يمنحنا نفس الشيء إلا أنه لا
keeps us away from not things that might eat us,
يبعدنا عن الأشياء التي يمكن أن تأكلنا
or heights, but rather things that might poison us,
أو المرتفعات فقط بل أيضاً الأشياء التي يمكن أن تسممنا
or give us disease and make us sick.
أو تصيبنا بمرض أو بالغثيان
So one of the features of disgust that makes it such
لذا فمن ملامح ألشعور بالقرف التي تجعله
an interesting emotion is that it's very, very easy to elicit,
مثيراً للإنتباه أنه من السهل جداً جداً اظهاره
in fact more so than probably any of the other basic emotions,
أكثر حتى من المشاعر الاخرى في الواقع
and so I'm going to show you that with a couple of images
لذا سأريكم ذلك بهذه الصور
I can probably make you feel disgust.
ربما سأجعلكم تشعرون بالقرف
So turn away. I'll tell you when you can turn back.
لذا إستديروا و سأعلمكم متى تنظرون
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I mean, you see it every day, right? I mean, come on. (Laughter)
أعني انكم ترون ذلك كل يومٍ .صحيح؟ أعني هيا .(ضحك)
(Audience: Ewww.)
الجمهور (إوووو)
Okay, turn back, if you didn't look.
حسنا إستديروا إذا لم تنظروا
Those probably made a lot of you in the audience
من المرجح أن هذه جعلت الكثير منكم فالجمهور
feel very, very disgusted, but if you didn't look,
يحسون بالقرف الشديد ، لكن إذا لم تنظروا
I can tell you about some of the other things that have been shown
يمكنني أن أخبركم عن الأشياء الأخرى التي وقع عرضها
sort of across the world to make people disgusted,
نوع من الأشياء العالمية التي تصيب الناس بالقرف
things like feces, urine, blood, rotten flesh.
أشياء مثل البراز و البول و الدم و السمك المتعفن
These are the sorts of things that it makes sense
هذه هي الأشياء التي من المنطقي
for us to stay away from, because they might actually contaminate us.
بالنسبة لنا أن نبقى بعيدين عنها لأنه من الممكن أن تلوثنا
In fact, just having a diseased appearance
في الواقع الأشكال المريضة
or odd sexual acts, these things are also
أو الأفعال الجنسية الغريبة ، هذه الأشياء أيضاً تصيبنا بالقرف
things that give us a lot of disgust.
تصيبنا بالكتير القرف
Darwin was probably one of the first scientists
من المرجح أن داروين كان من أوائل العلماء
to systematically investigate the human emotions,
الذين درسوا العواطف البشرية بطريقةٍ منهجية
and he pointed to the universal nature and the strength
وقد أشار إلى الطبيعة الكونية وقوة رد فعل القرف
of the disgust response.
رد فعل القرف.
This is an anecdote from his travels in South America.
هذه حكاية من سفراته في أمريكا الجنوبية
"In Tierro del Fuego a native touched with his finger
"في تيارو ديل فويغو، لمس أحد السكان الأصليين باصبعه
some cold preserved meat while I was eating ...
بعض اللحم البارد المحفوظ بينما كنت آكل
and plainly showed disgust at its softness, whilst I felt
.وأظهر بوضوحٍ قرفه من طراوته في حين شعرت
utter disgust at my food being touched by a naked savage — (Laughter) —
بالقرف التام لكون طعامي لمس من قبل همجي عار -(ضحك)-
though his hands did not appear dirty."
رغم أن يداه لم تبدوا متسختين".
He later wrote, "It's okay, some of my best friends are naked savages." (Laughter)
لقد كتب لاحقاً : لابأس البعض من أعز اصدقائي همجيون عارون.(ضحك)
Well it turns out it's not only old-timey British scientists
.حسنا، تبين أنه ليس فقط العلماء البريطانيون القدماء
who are this squeamish. I recently got a chance
شديدو الحساسية. مؤخرا، سنحت لي الفرصة
to talk to Richard Dawkins for a documentary,
للتحدث إلى ريتشارد داوكنز من أجل فيلم وثائقي
and I was able to disgust him a bunch of times. Here's my favorite.
و تمكنت من إثارة اشمئزازة في العديد المرات.هذه المفضلة لدي.
Richard Dawkins: "We've evolved around courtship and sex,
ريتشارد داكينز: " نحن نتمحور حول المغازلة و الجنس,
are attached to deep-rooted emotions and reactions
مرطبتون بالعواطف العميقة المتأصلة و ردود الأفعال
that are hard to jettison overnight."
التي من الصعب التخلص من في عشية و ضحاها".
David Pizarro: So my favorite part of this clip is that
دافيد بيزارو: هذا الجزء المفضل لدي في مقطع الفيديو هو أن
Professor Dawkins actually gagged.
برفيسور داكوينز فعلااً تقيأ.
He jumps back, and he gags, and we had to do it three times,
قفز للخلف, و تقيأ, و فعل ذلك ثلاث مرات,
and all three times he gagged. (Laughter)
و في الثلاث مرات تقيأ.(ضحك)
And he was really gagging. I thought he might throw up on me, actually.
و كان في الواقع يتقيأ, لدرجة انني أعتقد أنه تقيأ علي.
One of the features, though, of disgust,
من خصائص الشعور بالقرف ايضاً
is not just its universality and its strength,
ليس فقط عامية أو قوته,
but the way that it works through association.
ولكن الطريقة التي يعمل من خلال الشراكة او الترابط .
So when one disgusting thing touches a clean thing,
لذلك عندما يلمس شيء مقرفشيء اخر نظيف,
that clean thing becomes disgusting, not the other way around.
هذا الشيء النظيف يصبح مقرف, و ليس بالعكس.
This makes it very useful as a strategy if you want to
هذا يجعله استراتجية مفيده لو أردت أن
convince somebody that an object or an individual
تقنع شخص ما أن شيء أو شخص
or an entire social group is disgusting and should be avoided.
أو المجموعة كاملة مقرفة و يجب اجتنابها.
The philosopher Martha Nussbaum points this out
الفيلسوفه مارثا نوسباوم اشارت الي
in this quote: "Thus throughout history, certain disgust
في هذا لاقتباس" و هكذا علي مر التاريخ, قرف بعينة
properties -- sliminess, bad smell, stickiness, decay, foulness --
خصائص مثل-- القذارة والرائحة السيئة، اللزوجة، تسوس الاسنان، البذاءة -
have been repeatedly and monotonously been associated with ...
اصبحت مرتبظة مراراً و تكراراً مع
Jews, women, homosexuals, untouchables, lower-class people --
اليهود, النساء, المثلييون جنسياً, المنبوذين, و الناس من الطبقة الدنيا ----
all of those are imagined as tainted by the dirt of the body."
كلهم تم تصويرهم كحثالة المجتمع".
Let me give you just some examples of how, some powerful
دعوني اعطيكم بعض الامثلة عن كيف, بعض المثلة القوية
examples of how this has been used historically.
عن كيف كان هذا يستخدم تاريخياً.
This comes from a Nazi children's book published in 1938:
جاء هذا من كتاب أطفال نازي نشر في سنة 1938:
"Just look at these guys! The louse-infested beards,
" فقط أنظر علي هؤلاء النااس! اللحي المقملة الموبوءة,
the filthy, protruding ears, those stained, fatty clothes...
و الأذن الناتئة القذرة ، تلك الملابس الملطخة الدهنية ......
Jews often have an unpleasant sweetish odor.
اليهود لديهم دائما رأحة’ منفرة.
If you have a good nose, you can smell the Jews."
لو لديك حلسة شم قوية, يمكنك شم رائحة اليهود.
A more modern example comes from people who try to
مثال أكثر حداثة ياتي من النلس الذين
convince us that homosexuality is immoral.
يردون اقناعنا ان المثلية الجنسية غير أخلاقية.
This is from an anti-gay website, where they said
هذا من موقع ضد الشواذ جنسياًو حيث يقول
gays are "worthy of death for their vile ... sex practices."
الشواذ " يستحقون القتل لممارستهم الجنسية الدنيئة".
They're like "dogs eating their own vomit and sows wallowing in their own feces."
هم مثل" الكلاب الذين يأكلون قيئهم يتمرغون في برازهم".
These are disgust properties that are trying to be directly
هذه هي خصائص القرف التي تحاول ان تكون موجه
linked to the social group that you should not like.
و متصلة بفصيل اجتماعي يجب عليك نبذة
When we were first investigating the role of disgust in
عندما كنا ندرس دور القرف في
moral judgment, one of the things we became interested in
الحكم الاخلاقي, من الاشياء التي اثارت اهتمامنا
was whether or not these sorts of appeals are more likely
هي, سواء كانت هذه المناشدات علي الاغلب
to work in individuals who are more easily disgusted.
تعمل مع الاشخاص الذين من السهل ان يقرفوا.
So while disgust, along with the other basic emotions,
وبينما يكون الاشمئزاز، كالعواطف الأساسية الأخرى
are universal phenomena, it just really is true
ظواهر عالمية، فإنه في الحقيقة
that some people are easier to disgust than others.
بعض الناس يسهل اثارة اشمئزازهم اكثر من البعض الآخر
You could probably see it in the audience members
من الممكن أن تري ذلك في الجمهور
when I showed you those disgusting images.
عندما اريتكم هذة الصور المقرفة.
The way that we measured this was by a scale that was
الطريقة التي قسنا بها ذلك عن طريق مقياس
constructed by some other psychologists
صمم من قبل بعض علماء النفس أخرىن
that simply asked people across a wide variety of situations
ببساطة سألوا الناس عبر مجموعة متنوعة من المواقف
how likely they are to feel disgust.
ما مدى احتما لية شعورهم بالقرف
So here are a couple of examples.
هنا بعض الأمثلة.
"Even if I were hungry, I would not drink a bowl of my
" حتي و لو كنت جائعاً, لن أشرب اناء من
favorite soup if it had been stirred by a used but thoroughly washed fly-swatter."
شربتي المفضلة rقلبت بمنشة ذباب مستعملة و مغسولة".
"Do you agree or disagree?" (Laughter)
"هل توافقون ام لا؟"(ضحك)
"While you are walking through a tunnel under a railroad track,
" بينما انت تمشي داخل نفق تحت قضبان السكة الحديدية,
you smell urine. Would you be very disgusted or not at all disgusted?"
تشم رائحة بول. هل ستشعر بالقرف ؟ او لن تشعر بالقرف علي الاطلاق".
If you ask enough of these, you can get a general overall
لو سالتم الكثير من هذا النوع من الاسئلة, يمكنكم الوصول الي درجة عامة
score of disgust sensitivity.
للحساسية من القرف.
It turns out that this score is actually meaningful.
و اتضح ان هذة الدرجة لها معني.
When you bring people into the laboratory and you ask
عندما تحضر الناس الي المعمل و تسألهم
them if they're willing to engage in safe but disgusting behaviors
هل لديهم الرغبة في الاشتراك في ممارسات آمنة لكن مقرفة
like eating chocolate that's been baked to look like dog poop,
مثل اكل شكولاتة خبزت علي شكل براز الكلب,
or in this case eating some mealworms that are perfectly healthy but pretty gross,
أو في حالة اكل بعض الديدان الصحية جدا ولكن مقرفة,
your score on that scale actually predicts whether or not
درجتك علي هذا المقياس هي التي تحدد مدي رغبتك
you'll be willing to engage in those behaviors.
في الاشتراك في التجربة.
The first time that we set out to collect data on this
المرة الأولى التي شرعنا في جمع البيانات عن هذا
and associate it with political or moral beliefs,
وربطه مع المعتقدات السياسية أو الأخلاقية،
we found a general pattern --
وجدنا نمط العام -
this is with the psychologists Yoel Inbar and Paul Bloom --
هذا هو مع علماء النفس انبار يوئيل وبلوم بول -
that in fact, across three studies we kept finding
أن في الواقع، عبر ثلاث دراسات وجدنا
that people who reported that they were easily disgusted
أن الأشخاص الذين ابلغ عنهم أنهم سريعوا الشعور بالقرف
also reported that they were more politically conservative.
أيضا اكثر تحفظاً سياسياً.
Another way to say this, though, is that people
بطريقة اخري , يمكن القول ايضا, ان الاشحاص
who are very liberal are very hard to disgust. (Laughter)
الاكثر ليبرالية من الصعب ان نقرفهم.( ضحك)
In a more recent follow-up study, we were able to look at
وفي دراسة متابعة جديدة، كنا قادرين على دراسة
a much greater sample, a much larger sample. In this case,
عينة اعظم , اكبر بكثير. في هذة الحالة,
this is nearly 30,000 U.S. respondents,
حوالي ثلاثين الفا مستجيب امريكيا,
and we find the same pattern. As you can see,
وو جدنا نفس النمط. كما تروا,
people who are on the very conservative side
الاشخاص علي الجانب المحافظ
of answering the political orientation scale are
من الاجابة علي مقياس التوجه السياسي هم
also much more likely to report that they're easily disgusted.
ايضاً الاكثر ميلاً للشعور بالقرف بسهولة.
This data set also allowed us to statistically control
هذة البيانات تسمح لنا التحكم احصائياً
for a number of things that we knew were both related
في عدد الاشياء التي نعلم انهما مرتطبة
to political orientation and to disgust sensitivity.
بالتوجه السياسي وبالحساسية للقرف
So we were able to control for gender, age, income,
لذلك استطعنا التحكم في الجنس, العمر, الدخل,
education, even basic personality variables,
التعليم, حتي المتغيرات الشخصية,
and the result stays the same.
و النتيجة تبقي واحدة.
When we actually looked at not just self-reported political orientation,
عندما نظرنا ليس فقط من التقرير الشخصي عن التوجة السياسي,
but voting behavior, we were able to look geographically
و لكن ايضا كنا قادرين علي التحقق جغرافياً
across the nation. What we found was that in regions
عبر الامة. و ما وجدناه انه المناطق
in which people reported high levels of disgust sensitivity,
التي ابلغ ان الاشخاص لديها حساسية علية للقرف
McCain got more votes.
ماكيين تحصل علي عدد اصوات اكثر.
So it not only predicted self-reported political orientation,
لذلك انها لم تتوقع فقط التبليغ الشخصي عن التوجه السياسي
but actual voting behavior. And also we were able,
ولكن السلوك الانتخابي, و كنا قادرين,
with this sample, to look across the world,
باستخدام هذة العينة, النظر عبر العالم
in 121 different countries we asked the same questions,
في 121 دولة مختلفة, سالنا نفس الاسئلة
and as you can see, this is 121 countries collapsed
و كما تروا قسمت تلك الدول
into 10 different geographical regions.
الي 10 مناطق جغرافية مختلفة.
No matter where you look, what this is plotting is the size
لا يهم اين تنظر, ما يفرق هو
of the relationship between disgust sensitivity and political orientation,
العلاقة بين الحساسية للقرف و التوجة السياسي
and no matter where we looked, we saw a very similar effect.
و مهما نظرنا, نري نفس التاثيير.
Other labs have actually looked at this as well
و لقد قامت معامل اخري بدراسة هذا ايضاً
using different measures of disgust sensitivity,
باستخدام مقاييس مختلفة للحساسية بالقرف,
so rather than asking people how easily disgusted they are,
لذلك بدلا من سؤال الناس عن ما سهولة شعورهم بالقرف
they hook people up to physiological measures,
ربطوا الاشخاص بالمعايير الفسيولوجية,
in this case skin conductance.
في هذة الحالة ردة فعل الجلد.
And what they've demonstrated is that people who report
قد أثبتت الدراسة ان الناس الذين يبلغون
being more politically conservative are also more physiologically aroused
انهم متحفظون سياسيا ايضا من الاكثر اثارة فسيولوجياً
when you show them disgusting images like the ones that I showed you.
عندما تريهم صورا مقرفة كالتي عرضتها.
Interestingly, what they also showed in a finding
ومن المثير للاهتمام, ما توصلو الي
that we kept getting in our previous studies as well
هو ما توصلنا اليه مراراً في دراستنا السابقة
was that one of the strongest influences here is that
انة واحد من اقوي التاثيرات هنا هو
individuals who are very disgust-sensitive not only are
الاشخاص الذين الحساسون للقرف ليسوا فقط
more likely to report being politically conservative, but
اكثر تحفظا سياسيا, و لكن
they're also very much more opposed to gay marriage
هم ايضا معارضون جدا للزواج المثلي
and homosexuality and pretty much a lot of
و المثلية و الكثير من
the socio-moral issues in the sexual domain.
القضايا الاجتماعية والأخلاقية في المجال الجنسي.
So physiological arousal predicted, in this study,
لذلك الاثارة الفسيولوجية المتوقعة, في هذه الدراسة
attitudes toward gay marriage.
تجاه الزواج المثلي.
But even with all these data linking disgust sensitivity
ولكن بالرغم من البيانلت التي تربط الحاسية للقرف
and political orientation, one of the questions that remains is
و التوجة السياسي, احد الاسئلة المتبقية هو
what is the causal link here? Is it the case that
مال هو سبب هذة الصلة؟ هل هذة الحالة
disgust really is shaping political and moral beliefs?
الاشمئزاز يشكل حقيقة اللمعتقدات السياسية و الاخلاقية؟
We have to resort to experimental methods to answer this,
علينا اللجوء إلى الطرق التجريبية للإجابة على هذا،
and so what we can do is actually bring people into the lab
و ما يمكننا فعلة و الاستمرار في احضار الناس الي المعمل
and disgust them and compare them to a control group
و نثيير قرفهم و مقارنتهم مع المجموعة
that hasn't been disgusted. It turns out that over
التي لم يثار قرفهم. و اتضح انة خلال
the past five years a number of researchers have done this,
الخمس سنوات السابقة عدد من الباحثيين قاموا بذلك,
and by and large the results have all been the same,
و الي حد كبيير كانت النتائج واحدة,
that when people are feeling disgust, their attitudes
وا نة عندما يشعر الناس بالقرف , سلوكهم
shift towards the right of the political spectrum,
يتجه نحو الوؤي السياسية اليمينية,
toward more moral conservatism as well.
و في اتجاه التحفظ الاخلاقي ايضا
So this is whether you use a foul odor, a bad taste,
سواءً ما أ ستخدمت رائحة كريهة، اوطعم سيئ،
from film clips, from post-hypnotic suggestions of disgust,
من مقاطع الفيلم ، ومن قبل الاقتراحات المنومة من الاشمئزاز،
images like the ones I've shown you, even just
صور كالتي عرضتها لكم, فقط كي
reminding people that disease is prevalent and they should
اذكر الناس أن المرض منتشر وينبغي
be wary of it and wash up, right, to keep clean,
ان يكونوا حذرين من ذلك ويغتسلوا بشكل صحيح، للحفاظ على النظافة،
these all have similar effects on judgment.
كل هذا لة تأثيير مشابه من الحكم.
Let me just give you an example from a recent study
دعوني اعطيكم مثال من دراسة حديثة
that we conducted. We asked participants
قمنا باجراءها. سألنا المتطوعين
to just simply give us their opinion of a variety of social groups,
اعطاء ارائهم حول مجموعة مختلفة من عينات المجتمع,
and we either made the room smell gross or not.
و كنا نجعل الغرفة ذو رائحة سيئة او لا.
When the room smelled gross, what we saw was that
عندما كانت رائحة الغرفة مقزز, ما رأيناه هو ان
individuals actually reported more negative attitudes toward gay men.
الاشخاص في الواقع كان انطباعهم عن الرجال المثليين سلبي.
Disgust didn't influence attitudes toward all the other
القرف لم يؤثر في سلوك كل
social groups that we asked, including African-Americans,
عينات المجتمع التي قمنا بسؤالهم, بما في ذلك الأمريكيين من أصل أفريقي،
the elderly. It really came down to the attitudes they had
و كبار السن. انها في الواقع ترجع انطباعهم
toward gay men.
عن المثليين من الرجال.
In another set of studies we actually simply reminded people --
في مجموعة اخري من الدراسات قمنا نتذكير الناس ببساطة
this was at a time when the swine flu was going around --
انه في وقت انتشار مرض انفلوانزا الخنازيير
we reminded people that in order to prevent the spread
ذكرنا الناس بانه لكي نوقف انتشار
of the flu that they ought to wash their hands.
الانفلوانزا يتعين عليهم غسل أيديهم.
For some participants, we actually had them take questionnaires
بالنسبة لبعض المشاركين، اضطررنا في الواقع لجعلهم أخذ الاستبيانات
next to a sign that reminded them to wash their hands.
بجوار لافتة تذكرهم بغسل ايديهم.
And what we found was that just taking a questionnaire
و ما وجدنا انه مجرد اخذ الاستبيان
next to this hand-sanitizing reminder made individuals
بجوار لافتة التذكير بتعقيم الايدي جعلت الاشخاص
report being more politically conservative.
تبين انهم متحفظون سياسيا
And when we asked them a variety of questions about
و عندما سألنهم مجموعة من الاسئلة عن
the rightness or wrongness of certain acts, what we also
الصح و الخطأ لتصرف ما, و ايضا
found was that simply being reminded that they ought
وجدنا أنه بمجرد تذكيرهم بوجوب
to wash their hands made them more morally conservative.
غسل ايديهم جعلتهم اكثر تحفظاً من الناحية الاخلاقية.
In particular, when we asked them questions about
بالتحديد, عندما سألناهم أسئلة عن
sort of taboo but fairly harmless sexual practices,
نوع من الممارسات الجنسية المحظورة لكن غير مؤذية إلى حد ما
just being reminded that they ought to wash their hands
فقط بمجرد التذكير بانه يتعين عليهم غسل أيديهم
made them think that they were more morally wrong.
جعلتهم يعتقدون أنهم كانوا أكثر خطأ من الناحية الأخلاقية.
Let me give you an example of what I mean by harmless
دعوني اعطيكم مثال ماذا اعني بكلمة غير مؤذي
but taboo sexual practice. We gave them scenarios.
و لكن ممارسات جنسية محظورة
One of them said a man is house-sitting for his grandmother.
احدهم قال يحرس منزل جدتة
When his grandmother's away, he has sex with his girlfriend
عندما ذهبت جدتة بعيدا, كان يمارس الجنس مع صديقته
on his grandma's bed.
في سرير جدتة.
In another one, we said a woman enjoys masturbating
و في اخري, قلنا أمرأة كانت تمارس العادة السرية
with her favorite teddy bear cuddled next to her. (Laughter)
مع دميتها المفضلة معانقة بجانبها.(ضحك)
People find these to be more morally abhorrent
الناس يجدون هذا يكون مكروهاً أخلاقيا
if they've been reminded to wash their hands. (Laughter)
لو ذكروا بغسل أيديهم. (ضحك)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Okay. The fact that emotions influence our judgment
حسنا. حقيقة أن العواطف تؤثر حكمنا
should come as no surprise. I mean,
يجب ان لا تدهشنا. أعني
that's part of how emotions work.
انها جزء من كيفية عمل العواطف.
They not only motivate you to behave in certain ways,
أنها لا تحفزك فقط لتتصرف بطرق معينة,
but they change the way you think.
و لكنها تغير طريقة تفكيرك
In the case of disgust, what is a little bit more surprising
في حالة القرف, ما يعتبر مفاجأً نوع ما
is the scope of this influence. It makes perfect sense,
هو نطاق هذا التأثير. أنه من المعقول،
and it's a very good emotion for us to have, that disgust
وانها عاطفة جيدة جدا ان تكون لدينا، وهذا الاشمئزاز
would make me change the way that I perceive
سوف يجعلني أغير الطريقة التي انظر بها
the physical world whenever contamination is possible.
الي العالم المادي مهما كانت احتمالية تلويثة.
It makes less sense that an emotion that was built
انها تجعل من غير المعقول للاحساس الذي خلق
to prevent me from ingesting poison should predict
لمنعي من تناول السم يجب ا ن يتوقع
who I'm going to vote for in the upcoming presidential election.
من الذي سأنتخبة في السباق الرئاسي القادم.
The question of whether disgust ought to influence
السؤال حول ما إذا كان الاشمئزاز سيؤثر في
our moral and political judgments
اخلاقنا و احكامنا السياسية
certainly has to be complex, and might depend on exactly
وبالتأكيد يجب أن تكون معقدة، وربما تعتمد بالضبط علي
what judgments we're talking about, and as a scientist,
ما الحكم الذي نتحدث عنه, و كعالم,
we have to conclude sometimes that the scientific method
يجب علينا نستنتج في بعض الأحيان أن المنهج العلمي
is just ill-equipped to answer these sorts of questions.
هو مجرد سوء اعداد للرد على هذا النوع من الأسئلة.
But one thing that I am fairly certain about is,
و لكن هناك شيء واحد انا متأكد منه
at the very least, what we can do with this research is
على أقل تقدير، ما يمكننا أن نفعل بهذا البحث هو
point to what questions we ought to ask in the first place.
إشارة إلى ما هي الأسئلة التي يجب علينا أن نسألها في المقام الأول.
Thank you. (Applause)
شكراً لكم ( تصفيق)